recall that if I had two different
logical statements P and Q then I could
have the conditional between them that
said if P then Q and I can do the same
idea not just between two different
statements but between two different
predicates so that's what the idea of a
universal conditional is so we use this
notation P of X and notice that it's a a
double arrow opposed to a single arrow
here a P of X which is a predicate is
going to imply a different predicate Q
of X and what I mean by that is that
every time I put it in an input then the
predicate becomes a statement so what
I'm saying is for every possible input
in my domain or for every X inside of my
domain then the statement P of X where I
plugged in a specific value of X implies
the statement Q of X for that same value
of x so in other words a universal
conditional is going to be just like a
normal conditional but where your
statements are replaced by predicates
and then the condition will work for
every single input value so let's take a
look at this mathematical sentence this
has two different predicates inside of
it first of all I have if X is the POTUS
if X is the president of the United
States
that's a predicate and I will call it P
of X and then it says that if this is
going to be true then X is a US citizen
and I'll write that as a second
predicate so depending on what your X is
some X's if X has sort of lives in the
universe of people for instance if I set
my domain to be equal to just humans
some of those people are US citizens
some of those people are US presidents
and what this claim is is that all the
ones that are US presidents that set of
people throughout history all of those
people are US citizens note that when I
phrase it here as an if
as a conditional that the universal part
they for all X in the people part is
just sort of not explicitly written but
it still is they're implicitly when I
say if X is going to be the president
United States I am saying for all people
that happen to be the president of the
United States so this is sort of the
equivalence between these two ideas
saying if some predicate is going to be
true in other words if X has the
property of being the president noted
states is the same thing as saying for
all people or every person who is the
president United States they are those
people are then going to become US
citizens another way to phrase this is
sort of natural English that might make
the for all or the every more explicit
is something like this every president
of the United States is a US citizen I
haven't put it in my formal if-then
conditional form but the every that I
have here is the same thing as this for
all right every is kind of like a for
all so this is saying every president of
the United States is the same thing as
if X is the president of States is a US
citizen same thing as that X is a US
citizen